hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the Tosca automation
in this session I am going to take you
through some of the reporting options
which are available with Tosca
now we have already seen in some of the
other videos that we can directly uh
using the print view option we can
directly capture or we can directly
create a report for our specific section
or folder uh as it is right so if I have
got this execution okay and if I want to
look at this login user execution
okay with all the objects expanded here
so if I click on print View and then I
can directly print it as a page but
apart from that there are other options
like you can generate a report in any of
these formats so for example if I want
to generate it in the PDF format or the
word excel format or the HTML format so
I need to select that format and then
click on start
and then Tosca will generate a HTML file
and then it will be displayed or opened
in the browser okay so it's exactly the
same uh snapshot of whatever you have
opened on your Tosca screen
so it's not the most attractive report
but at least you have got a report in
just a few seconds by just going to the
print view option
but apart from that you have also got
the reporting section okay so where you
can generate some reports now if you're
not able to see this reporting section
then you can always go to the section
and click on reporting and it will open
this uh section called reporting okay
now in the reporting section
um there are some default reports which
you can generate and it they are listed
here so that is execution list and here
you can see you can generate uh
executional entries with actual log
execution enters with actual login it
shows with detailed logs similarly for
requirements and for test cases okay so
these are some of the default report
definitions and data definitions which
have been already provided uh by Tosca
so you can always use this to generate
your own report so say for example let's
take this particular scenario the
end-to-end scenario which we looked
earlier right so we have built this
business test case uh with our execution
list linked to it right and then if you
want to kind of generate a report out of
it so what we can do is we can generate
it from the demo shop okay
or any particular folder right from here
also we can generate so right click on
any particular execution list folder and
go to print report and you will see all
those default report definitions which
are present here for the execution
entries okay so if you do it for test
cases it will be for test case for
requirements it will be the requirements
so these are the four types of report
definitions which have been provided
already
and I can choose any of these okay so
for example if I choose execution
entries with actual log or execution
entries with detailed logs okay so if I
choose this
it will basically generate a report uh
it will again take you to this print
option screen but the report will be
little bit different okay because it is
based on a report definition rather than
just printing out whatever is present on
this page so if I click on start now
again it will export a document
and then it will ask you for some
options like do you want only field
stations to be shown I said no
then it is asking do you want
screenshots included I will say yes in
between
okay
and then it will generate a proper
report now you can always change this
logo which is it is displaying currently
transientist but you can also change
this uh in the report section
um and then it will show you an
execution test report it was created on
this particular date
and then it will show you a summary with
how many test cases failed okay with a
pie chart
and then what was failed okay so uh
everything is displayed here right
similarly you can generate it for any
particular document right so I can
generate it for the whole execution list
as well so if I go here print report and
then execution entries with detailed
logs
okay and then start again save and then
okay
and yes
okay so it will export it into a proper
document now and now you can see a
proper view of all the execution lists
okay so all the test cases like we're 10
19 test cases and three past 14 node
result and to failed
uh a sum up pie chart
and then it the individual execution
list of
what were the results of these execution
lists right
so here you can see for register user it
is showing all the steps as well uh when
it's
when it was started when it ended and
who executed it uh with all the login
for as well right which screenshots
Whenever there is a failure so it's a
proper report which you can generate
right from any particular folder or any
particular object for that matter okay
so this is where you can use the default
reporting definitions which are already
provided in your workspace but if you
want to also generate your own report
definition that also you can do so right
click on the reporting folder and there
you will find a create report definition
so click on that and you will see that
there is an exclamation mark on the
report definition uh which means that
something is not configured properly
right so first we need to select a data
set definition okay and it should be
linked to a particular object so what
kind of object you want to link it to so
I can basically select one of the
execution list if I wanted to link it to
an execution list if I want to link it
to a test case I can select any test
case object or requirement or module
whatever you want to do okay so if I
select this and drag it to report
definition folder you will see the link
uh now it is the object type has been
updated to execution list okay
but still there is an exclamation mark
which means we also need to provide a
designer definition now to assign a
designer definition right click here and
then in create designer definition we
have got three different options so the
first is default and this allows you to
design your report with the report
designer so there is a third party tool
through which you can design your own
report basically change the text or
change the header headers or Footers and
Logo so all those things you can do uh
with the report designer so that will
only be possible if you choose this
default option
there is also XML report so this will
create an XML document containing all
generated information and then the Excel
report will create a worksheet in
Microsoft Excel with all the information
for every data definition
so if you select default now you will
see the exclamation mark is gone so this
is a proper report definition now this
is pretty similar to what you see which
are currently present here right so
these are built for execution entries
with actual log right now keep in mind
that uh you need to also provide more uh
specially objects right so here this is
just the object type which has been set
after this you need to create another
data set definition and there you need
to provide a proper tql query which can
identify or which can search that object
on the workspace okay or else you can
select this link and then the object
type here so that uh it it is able to
search that particular data set okay so
for example like this end to end
scenario
so which is a business execution list so
if I say end to end
okay uh scenario and then execution list
so here uh we can now Define our own
um own query
so for that you also need to choose that
equal query column Chooser in the column
Chooser right so here you can Define
your own SQL query right
or else you can use this link in object
type and constraint to basically build
that okay so choice is yours uh for
example uh if I go here in subparts and
then object type okay
so I choose object type as execution
list and then in constraint I need to
put a constraint something like name
equals equals
um and then I will provide end-to-end
scenario in this
okay so that will build a constraint
and this will basically act as a t equal
query you can see the equal query is
built as you keep on selecting the
required object type constraint and Link
okay
so uh this way you can build your report
definition your own report definition
and then you can print the report based
on this report definition rather than
using some of the default ones but if
you quickly want to generate a report
like I showed you you can use this
default uh report definitions which are
good enough for execution lists or
for requirements or test cases but if
you want something of your own
customized report then you can build uh
your own report definition okay
so this was a quick overview about the
reporting section how you can quickly
generate reports
using the default report definitions and
you can also generate your or create
your own report definitions
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments
if you like this video then please
subscribe to our Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video